Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
(birds chirping)
(rooster crows)
(door opens)
(car engine tries to start)
(car engine starts)
MAN (on radio):
Good morning, Lula.
This is the "Weverend"
Beverly H. Hooker.
It's gonna be another hot one
here in the central valley.
Temperatures up around 99.
Now let's
get things started with
the Heaven on a Hookup Singers.
♪ I've been up
I've been down ♪
♪ Been lookin' for some joy
to come around ♪
♪ I've been praying
for some sunshine ♪
♪ Been lookin' for a love
that I can call mine ♪
♪ See, I've cried
for so long ♪
♪ Now I'm ready for the tears
to be gone, so ♪
♪ I'm calling you right now ♪
-♪ Right now ♪
♪ 'Cause you said that I could
make it, Lord, anyhow ♪
-♪ So I'm goin' away ♪
-♪ Are you ♪
- ♪ 'Cause I know that
you're gonna pull ♪
- ♪ Me through ♪
-♪ I hear you telling me to ♪
-♪ Be strong ♪
-♪ 'Cause deliverance
is comin' in ♪
-♪ It won't be long ♪
-♪ The storm will pass ♪
-♪ How we ♪
-♪ I believe it's gonna be ♪
-♪ A brighter day ♪
-♪ I can finally see ♪
-♪ The sun ♪
-♪ So I'm waitin' on you till ♪
-♪ Thy kingdom come ♪
WOMAN: Bud, we got a letter
from your sister this morning.
BUD:
Well, I ain't readin' it.
-WOMAN: Fine. I'll read it.
-BUD : Well, I ain't
listenin'.
WOMAN: That's fine too.
You don't even have to listen.
"Dear Brother and Raynelle,
Well, Bud, I was expecting
to see you at services Sunday,
but I guess there
must have been something
good on the TV... again.
I know how you love to watch
that wrestling program...
BUD:
Damn straight.
- WOMAN: ..."I wonder if they'll
have TV in hell.
-(Bud scoffs)
WOMAN: Well, I heard about
Junior and Charisse's business
going belly-up.
When will
that son of yours learn?"
BUD: She should talk.
One boy in the pen,
and the other on the way.
WOMAN: "I think both our sons
could learn a thing or two from
Buster Kincaid's boy, Tiny.
-Thank you very much.
- WOMAN: "I had him
over here Saturday...
and that boy mowed
the front yard, the side yard
the backyard,
plus them three acres I got
out behind the house.
Since his birthday
is coming up next week,
I gave him three dollars
instead of the usual two.
Well, that's about
all the news for now.
I've decided to come over
and visit y'all next Sunday
after services.
One of you--
and I'm not saying who, Bud--
needs to get right
with the Lord.
And I'm just the lady
for the job.
We're gonna spend
the whole day in prayer,
discussing Scripture...
and singing hymns
till we wear you down.
-Like it says in II Peter 3:8,
-(Bud gasping)
'One day is with the Lord
as a thousand years.'
Your loving sister,
Marguerite."
Well, Bud, what did
you think of that?
(thud)
Bud.
(ringing)
(ring)
Hello?
♪ Blessed assurance ♪
♪ Jesus is mine ♪
♪ O what a foretaste
of glory divine ♪
Oh, hell no!
-(dial tone)
-You're not gonna get off
that easy.
(phone ringing)
-God!
-(ring)
-Good God, Mama!
-Did I hear you just take
the Lord's name in vain?
-What the hell do you want?
-Don't talk filthy!
And what are you doing,
still laying in the bed?
It's 7:00 in the morning.
How come you're not up
looking for a job?
I'm not out looking for a job
because it's 7:00
in the morning.
Oh, you wouldn't happen
to be suffering from a hangover,
would you? Hmm?
Are you laid up there
with some harlot, huh?
Harlot!
-No! Mama, stop it!
-(slapping phone)
Wake up, harlot.
What time is it?
Harlot! Harlot!
Can you hear me in there?
Oh, Mama, stop that.
Wh--What do you want?
I just thought
you might wanna know...
your uncle Bud...
he passed this morning.
I'm sorry to hear that, Mama.
How's Aunt Raynelle doing?
Well, how do you think
she's doing, huh?
Her husband just dropped dead
at the breakfast table,
in the middle
of one of my letters.
Mm. Imagine that.
So, we are gonna
have to go over there
and give them some comfort...
and some Christian counsel.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
What do you mean "we"?
Are you telling me that you're
gonna turn your back on your
family in this time of tragedy?
Mama, all them folk over there at
that house and--and you're telling
me somebody can't come get you?
-Come on,
call Junior or Ray Bud.
-They have too much to do!
And I would just die of shame
if people knew that my own son
didn't want to take me over...
to comfort my only brother's
grieving widow.
Or maybe you'd like to see me
walk the 20 miles to Lula.
It's 110 in the shade.
Or maybe you'd like me
to drop dead from a heatstroke.
All right, all right, Mama.
Ok, already. What time
do you wanna leave?
Well, what time do you think
I wanna go, next month?
Boy, get your triflin',
worthless self over here now!
Bud ain't gonna keep long
in this heat.
RAYNELLE:
Now, Reverend, are you sure
I can't offer you a ham?
I've got three of them,
and it's just before noon.
No, no, no, thank you.
That's mighty kind of you.
You know,
it must be a blessing,
having your daughter here
living with you during this time
of "beweavement."
Oh, yes, it is.
You've met my daughter,
Delightful, haven't you?
Yes, yes,
I believe I have.
-She's so precious to me.
-I can see why.
REVEREND HOOKER (clears
throat): Well, sister,
being that Brother Bud
wasn't a "wegular" member
of the church,
I was hoping you'd tell me
a little something
about your late husband...
that, uh, I can include
in my "wemarks."
Um, it doesn't have to
be anything fancy.
Just in your own words,
what kind of man
was Brother Bud.
Well... he was mean.
-Mean.
-Mean as a snake.
-I see.
-And surly.
Surly.
Sister, I didn't know
Brother Slocumb well,
but to me,
he seemed a quiet man.
REVEREND HOOKER: A man
of inner strength.
A man that knew his own mind,
kept his own counsel...
and was at peace
with the world.
A wise, noble, gentle man.
Well, that's 'cause
you didn't know him
till he got old and sick,
but he was mean
and he was right surly.
(sighs)
Sister, in my experience,
it's best to remember
the happier times.
Well, they were few
and far between.
RAYNELLE: Let me explain
something to you, Reverend.
After my two boys
were born,
I decided I wanted to
go back to church.
And one time we went up
to a revival meeting,
and I got saved.
And I was so happy,
I came rushing back
to tell Bud.
He hit the ceiling.
Cursed me out like I'd never
been cursed out by anybody.
I said, "Bud, we're talking
about your immortal soul here.
And if you don't take yourself
up to that revival meeting,
your soul is gonna
be in danger forever."
He wasn't having
any part of it.
So, I said, "Well, if that's
the way you feel about it,
I'm just gonna cut you off
altogether."
I--I beg your pardon?
Not so much as a warm
handshake in 20 years.
RAYNELLE: Well, except
for that one time.
(crunching)
Well, I believe I have
all the information
I'm gonna need.
All right.
(chattering)
WOMAN: I just don't know
what I'm gonna say.
Lord knows how I'm gonna
get through this.
I mean, all our humiliation
knowing that Daddy Bud
up and died...
knowing that you never made
nothing of yourself, Junior.
Never.
Lord knows
it's gonna be sad
sittin' there thinking how...
Daddy Bud died knowing
we had to sell everything...
to move into that
god-awful trailer to pay off
that big ol' dream of yours.
(children chattering)
Maybe you oughta set
that to music, Charisse.
I mean, that sure should bring
a tear to everybody's eye.
I believe I was just
stating the facts, Junior.
I loved him too.
He was like my own daddy.
BOY: Mom, he kicked me.
And you know
something else, Junior?
I was just sitting here
thinking to myself,
your family never loved me.
Never! They're just lookin'
down on us right now...
just having themselves
a good ol' laugh--
ha ha ha!
Whoever thought of a machine
that cleans parking lots?
I mean, really!
All our money
just right down the crapper.
Whoosh!
Just gone.
-(chattering)
-What? Damn it, boy!
Damn shoe!
Now, look, walk around
with one on your foot now!
-(children laughing)
-You know what?
I could have been
a professional, you know.
-I had talent.
-Talent? (laughs)
Oh, and let me tell you
something else, Mr. Funny Man.
I could have been lap-tied
to your cousin,
Teddy Wayne Slocumb,
and been the wife
of the lawyer.
Keep pushing it,
Charisse.
CHARISSE: But oh, no,
I couldn't think about myself.
Uh-uh. I had to listen
to my foolish heart...
and get married to a fool.
A dreamer that just spent
all our money on his dream.
-I'm gonna kill us, Charisse.
-Oh, please.
I'm gonna kill us.
You ain't gonna kill nobody.
I'm gonna kill us!
-I'm gonna kill us!
-(maniacal laughing)
(Charisse screaming)
(tires skid)
Shut up!
Just shut it up!
All right?
My daddy just died.
Can you understand that?
My daddy just died,
I'm 33 years old,
I'm dead broke,
I got no money,
no job, no prospects,
three kids,
and worst of all,
I'm married to you.
Now just shut it up!
Just shut up!
Whoo! I swear
my hand before God,
you say one more word
about parking lots,
I will kill you.
And me too.
You got that?
Do you got that?
You would have to get a job
and buy some bullets first,
Junior.
Put that thing away.
Put it away!
How dare you pull that out
in front of these kids!
Now you know your daddy
was just playing.
He really love us.
He love us.
You know Daddy just goes through
a little something sometimes.
Isn't that right, baby?
Y'all play nice now.
(children laughing,
chattering)
WOMAN: Ray Bud,
I'm trying to make your daddy's
funeral arrangements in here.
Okay, right now
I'm guessing that Ray Bud's
mother and sister...
will probably be riding
in the hearse with the body,
so, um, tell Antoine--
-(mumbles)
-Oh, he does?
Well, what if one of us
drove it? Ray Bud's
a real good driver.
Tell her we'll just toss him
on the back of the truck.
Listen, honey, I--I'm gonna
have to let you go, okay?
I got family comin'
and not a thing to eat
in this house.
So, I'll just stop by later
this afternoon, okay?
And we'll work out
the rest of the details
then, okay?
Okay. Okay.
Okay.
Thanks, Merline.
What the hell
you thanking her for?
The damn thieves!
Ray!
Whoever thought of the term
"grave robber" had Antoine
and Merline's calendar...
-hanging on their wall.
-Now, Ray, let's just stay calm.
Look, I'll find your shirt.
And what's my daddy doing
down at Depew's, anyway?
That's what I'd like to know.
The Slocumbs have always
gone to Patterson's.
Well, you know, I thought that
was strange too, but Depew's
is what your mama wanted.
(scoffs)
It's revenge. That's what it is.
-He's got me where he wants.
-What are you talking about?
Antoine Depew.
Remember fourth grade
when he peed his pants?
-"P.U. here comes Depew."
-You started that?
I started it. I started it, and
it followed him all the way
through high school.
Ray, now you're starting
to talk a little crazy now.
Look, you know how I feel
about funerals, Lucille.
I don't like funerals.
People coming up to you,
wanting to know what you feel.
-It doesn't make a difference
what people think. -Honey,
listen to me. All right just...
It's all right, okay?
Just relax.
I know how hard
this is for you.
I know you had your problems
with your daddy, but...
we're family, and we're
gonna get through this
together, okay?
-Okay.
-Mm, there you go.
-And speaking of family,
-(sighs)
your Aunt Marguerite...
volunteered to spend the night
with your mama, isn't that good?
-That's good.
-Good. And, um...
Junior, Charisse and the kids
are gonna stay here with us.
-No! No! No!
-Ray Bud, he's your brother.
No. I'm not gonna have
Junior and them
mess around here.
-They can go stay at a motel.
-Now you know they can't afford
a motel.
Is that my fault? Did I
hold a gun to his head,
tell him to mortgage his house
and blow all that money
on that pipe dream?
Now you shouldn't talk about
your brother like that, Ray Bud.
He tried so hard.
Face it, Lucille.
He's an idiot, okay?
And I'm not gonna sit here
and listen to Charisse
running her mouth.
And them children
are demon-possessed.
Look, we'll talk about it
tonight. Here's your lunch.
But don't forget, you gotta
stop by the shoe store.
Size ten-D, okay?
-I'll remember, Lucille, okay?
-Good.
And Ray?
Now we're not gonna have
any problems, are we?
-No, Lucille, we're not
gonna have any problems.
-Good.
-You just do me one favor.
-What's that?
When I die,
don't tell nobody.
Bury me out in the backyard
and tell everyone I left you.
(starts engine)
♪ Layin' in the arms
of a mother ♪
♪ And like
a cool wind blowin' ♪
♪ In the middle
of the burning summer ♪
(Charisse, indistinct)
Tariq, what is that in your
mouth? What is wrong with you?
-Gimme that! Let it go!
-JUNIOR: Let the boy eat it.
CHARISSE: Let it go!
-J--Junior?
-What?
-What is this?
-I don't know.
Junior, this looks like
a woman's earring,
but it ain't mine.
Junior!
What?
-Whose is it?
-Oh, baby, I don't know that.
Oh, you don't know.
Oh you don... You want me to
help you remember? Is that It?
(all yelling)
-MAN: Ray Bud!
-Yeah.
(drill whirring)
Yeah.
It's all just a mystery,
ain't it?
-Life and death.
-(opens pop-top can)
(sighs)
Yes, it is, Clyde.
Yes, it is.
Ain't no easy thing
losing your daddy.
Yeah, he's the one
that taught you how to
bait that first hook,
whooped that ass to teach you
right from wrong,
bought you your first beer.
It's the good things
we remember.
Yep. I oughta get back
to this carburetor.
We're not
just a garage, Ray.
We're your family.
Back when you wasn't nothing
but a drunken bum,
didn't show up for work
half the time,
we stood by you.
Paid your bills,
lied to your wife.
That's what families do.
And I, uh, sure am grateful
for that, Clyde.
Course, now I wouldn't let
Antoine and Merline Depew...
bury my dog,
much less my daddy.
-(phone ringing)
-So, if you have any
problems whatsoever,
you just give us a call.
Thank you, Clyde.
I gotta get back.
Now, if, uh,
you just say the word,
Antoine and Merline
will be paying more
in hearse repair...
than they make in a year.
Thank you, Clyde.
I'll keep that in mind.
CLYDE: Clyde's.
Ray Bud,
it's your cousin, Royce.
This is Ray.
Where are you?
MARGUERITE:
Well, what did he say?
ROYCE: He say he'd be on his way
as soon as he could.
You just do this
to torture me, don't you?
Yeah, Mama, I siphoned out all
that gas so you and me could
spend some more time together.
You're a demon, Royce,
you know that? I swear to God
you're the devil incarnate.
Look, Mama, just keep
your drawers on, all right?
Ray Bud say he be here
as soon as he could.
And believe me,
he can't get here
fast enough to suit me.
So, let's just... let's just sit
here and be quiet for a while,
okay?
(scoffs)
-(rap music on radio)
- ♪ Mama don't you cry
don't you cry no more ♪
♪ Your baby boy's growin' up
and he's goin' to war ♪
♪ My mind is playing tricks
and my gat is too ♪
-(switches station)
-(radio static)
-(changes station)
- ♪ Hey, Lord ♪
♪ Let it be ♪
- ♪ Dear Lord ♪
-(changes station)
♪♪ (rap, indistinct)
- ♪ I...♪
-(changes station)
-♪♪ (rap, indistinct)
(both alternating
changing stations)
-(laughs) Jesus got the knob!
-♪♪ (religious)
(laughs)
That's cool, Mama.
-(laughing)
-Yeah, that's cool, 'cause
Satan's got the car keys.
-You gimme them keys, boy.
Give me them keys!
-Now. Uh-huh. No!
-Give 'em--
-No!
I can not believe, I spent 17
hours in labor with you!
You get back here!
Royce where you--
Get back here!
You get back here, boy!
Don't make me have to hurt you!
WOMAN: I think you'll find
that here at Depew's,
we combine a thrifty,
no-nonsense approach
with a Christ-like
sensitivity
to answer
all your funeral needs.
-Ahem.
-Yes.
Well, we have a number
of wonderful plans.
Let me just take you
through just a few of them.
(mouthing)
WOMAN: We have
the Eternal Life package.
MARGUERITE: Seventeen hours
of unbelievable torment.
Crying out
in unbearable agony.
Would it kill you to do
one thing to please me, huh?
It looks that way, Mama.
You know, ever since you got
fired from that sewage plant,
you've been hanging out
with that bad crowd.
Well, you're gonna end up
just like your brother,
aren't you?
Oh, Mama, come on now.
Leave Levar out of this!
Maybe they'll put you in a cell
right next to him up there
in Parkersville.
The two of you can play
on your harmonicas and beat
on the bars with your tin cups.
You know what? I aint' got
time for this. -You hear me
talkin' to you, boy.
-You wait up
and come back here!
-Mama, look.
There's a filling station
not more than two miles
down this road, all right?
I'm gonna walk down there
and go get some gas.
I'll be right back.
Well, go on get your gas.
If I'm lucky, I'll pass out
here in the middle of the road.
And some big semi come roll
over my head and that'll just
be the end of it.
You just walk
and get your gas!
(grumbling)
All right, Mama, all right.
Wh-what do you wanna talk about?
What are you gonna do
with yourself, Royce?
Them unemployment checks
are not gonna come forever,
you know.
Have you thought about that?
You thought about your future?
Huh?
Life is not just
drinkin' and dancin'
and a bunch of loose women.
-Life is not a good time Royce.
-Yeah, well, you're
livin' proof of that.
Boy, if you don't watch
your mouth, you gonna--
Whoo!
You better straighten up and fly
right. Or else you're gonna end up
dancin' on a bed of hot coal.
You better come up
with a plan, and you better
come up with it soon.
-I got a plan.
-Well, what is it?
Where is it?
Look, Mama, you right, okay?
Them unemployment checks
ain't gonna keep comin' in.
I know you don't think
I think about that, but I do.
And when they do stop coming in,
I'm gonna go ahead
and find me a nice gal.
A good Christian gal.
Go ahead and settle down.
Cut all this foolishness.
Mama, I know you always
wanted grandbabies.
You always said that.
I figure I'll go
and have me a couple kids,
one or two of them.
So I can get on welfare.
Welfare?
-Is that your plan?
-Yep, that's about it.
You wanna know
what I say to that?
(yelling, indistinct)
(arguing)
WOMAN: Now, look here.
Them folding chairs aren't
really part of your package,
but I guess I'll throw
them in this one time.
Thanks, Merline.
And could you bring back
those funeral wrappers
first thing in the morning?
-Okay. Bye.
-Bye-bye.
Oh, no, no, no, no!
Oh!
I have people coming.
What am I gonna do?
LUCILLE:
I hope Mama Raynelle
don't mind corn dogs.
♪ You'll not leave her by ♪
♪ Or stand
right by her side ♪
-♪ Know before you go ♪
-(chattering)
♪ Just know
that every woman needs ♪
♪ Her man ♪
-♪ Her man ♪
-Come on, Delightful.
What about this one?
I don't care, Mama.
Whatever you want.
Well, I like
the Diplomat, myself.
Who cares what you like, Satan?
Give it here.
G-Give it here!
I don't see where it
really matters anyway.
Oh, it does matter.
What you gonna do,
put him out in a pine box?
LUCILLE: Well, of course not,
Aunt Marguerite. Corn dog,
Mama Ray?
No, thank you.
-(Arguing)
-CHARISSE: You're a lying, dirty
man. Get out!
LUCILLE:
Junior, is Charisse
feeling all right?
Um, well, I-I-I think
she is, Lucille.
You know,
sometimes she gets
these sick headaches.
-Oh, that's too bad.
-Yeah.
-You want a corn dog?
-Oh, yeah. Uh, thank you,
Lucille.
You're welcome.
Take a napkin.
-Mm-hmm. All right.
-Okay.
-ROYCE: Thanks, Lucille.
-Y'all decide on anything?
No, Mama's just thinking
about some of the models.
You know, I say we go with
the-the Heavenly Express.
Oh, you do, do you?
-RAYNELLE: Well, it's pretty.
-It seems kind of pricey
to me, Mama.
-Fine.
-No, no, no, no, Ray, you can't
be thinking like that, man.
This is our one and only daddy,
and we're gonna do this
the right way.
Alright, look-look, me and Ray, we're
gonna handle this, and we ain't gonna
worry about how much it costs.
-Yeah?
-That's what family's for.
-I'll tell you what I think.
-Ray, honey, you wanna help
me...
with some more food
in the kitchen?
(door opens)
I don't mean
to interrupt.
Charisse, how you feeling?
Not well, Lucille.
Are my kids
driving you crazy?
Oh, no, honey.
We locked them outside.
-(pounding)
-Oh!
Get your little ass away.
Stop banging on the window
before you break it!
Man I ain't playin' with you.
Don't make me come out there.
-(clattering)
-I'll beat your ass
if your daddy won't.
Uh, Lucille, listen.
I didn't bring
any of my nerve pills.
-Can I borrow some
of yours, please?
-Oh, sure, honey.
-I'll be right back.
-Come on, precious.
Junior, get my shoe.
JUNIOR: Yes, ma'am.
(water running)
(sighs)
That's it.
There you go, sweetie.
I'm sorry to hear
you're not feeling well,
Charisse.
Mama Ray, I'm the one
that's sorry.
Because I know
what it feels like to watch
something that you love
just shrivel up and die
right before your very eyes.
It's sad.
Here you go, Charisse honey.
I brought you a double dose.
Lucille, thank you.
You are a comfort.
-You're welcome.
-Now-n-now, come on, honey,
we should just go...
and lay you down in the bedroom
so-so you can just rest.
(sighs)
Maybe you're right.
I am feeling a little faint.
There you go honey.
Whoo! Did I
just drop something?
Charisse.
I-I believe it's your earring.
This is not mine, Lucille.
Everybody, take a look
at this earring.
I would never,
ever wear something
so cheap and tawdry.
LUCILLE: Charisse, honey,
you might wanna be laying down
when them nerve pills kick in.
Now come on.
Come on, Charisse.
Mm-hmm. Gonna take just
a little thought, Junior,
'cause I know I know
who owns this earring.
-Okay, come on.
-That's all it takes is a little
thought baby.
'Cause I'm gonna find out
who it is. Uh-huh.
CHARISSE: I could have married
the rich Slocumb, Teddy Wayne.
(scoffs)
My vote's in for
the Heavenly Express.
Heavenly Express it is.
Now, can we get to the subject
of the headstone,
before we all fall dead?
I'm sure you got something
to say about it, Marguerite.
I think it would be nice
to have some Scripture
-on the headstone.
-(Ray clears throat)
And my first thought
was Ecclesiastics,
-chapter 2, verse 16.
-Aunt Marguerite, please.
"For there is no remembrance
of the wise more than
of the fool."
-Aunt Marguerite! Please!
-Seeing that which now
is in the days to come."
-No, no, no.
-No, what?
That would be good.
I mean, we can use some of that,
Mama.
-Yes.
-Look, look.
Could we just slow down
a little bit?
Now, Mama, Antoine said...
for the price of the stone,
we get Daddy's date of birth,
his name
and date of departure.
-Anything else is extra.
-How much, Ray?
-Two dollars a letter.
-How many words over there,
Aunt Marguerite?
-One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight, nine...
-(Ray sighs)
That, that little bit of Bible
ain’t gonna cost that much, Ray.
Well whatever it is,
it's a damn sight more
than you'll kick in, Junior.
So, what you saying, Ray?
Hmm? You saying I ain't
gonna pay my fair share?
Is that what you're saying, Ray?
It's easy for you to come on in
here and shoot your big mouth
off.
"Let's throw Daddy a big
funeral." You think he would
have done the same for you?
-Yes, I do.
-Well, you're dreaming.
This is the last time we've got
to show our Daddy we loved him.
All you can do
is sit up there and talk
about how much it's gonna cost.
Not everybody thinks about
money all the time, Ray.
Some of us don't think about
money any of the time.
That's why some of us
don't have two nickels
to rub together.
Ooh.
Ray, I saw that new used truck
you got out there.
You think I ain't seen that?
-So. -I heard about the trip
you took Lucille to Swamp
World last year.
-You think I ain't
heard about that?
-What about it?
You think I wouldn't want to take
my kids down there so they can
ride on some of them rides?
-Mm-hm. What about that, Ray?
-Yeah, what about it?
RAY: Why don't you take
those little monsters
out to the parking lot?
Let 'em ride around on that
little invention of yours,
whatever it is you made.
-So, now my kids
is monsters, huh?
-Yeah, they're monsters.
You talk about my machine too,
huh, Ray. Why you gotta bring my
kids into this, huh?
-You know what? You know what?
At least I got kids.
-Oh, you're a tough guy.
-JUNIOR: I'm gonna bite you,
sucker!
-Fool!
RAY: No, I don't think so.
-JUNIOR: Let me go
so I can kick your ass!
-Come on! Come on!
Come on! Come on boy!
-JUNIOR: You want some of this?
-Don't let him do that to you.
-Let me go so I can--
-Ray! Junior!
-(screaming)
-Ray! Ray!
-Stop it, stop it, stop it!
-(both grunting)
Stop it!
Stop, don't move at all!
Come here, Royce.
I want you to take this
down to Antoine's,
and I want you to tell him...
that this is what I want
on my husband's headstone.
RAYNELLE: Just 12 letters.
My wallet's
in the kitchen.
This will stay between us,
right, Royce?
Yes, ma'am.
I'm just gonna
get some air.
Don't say anything
to me.
-Sorry, Mama.
-Ugh.
LUCILLE: Ray! Mama Ray?
I cannot believe you grown
boys are acting like this
at a time like this when your
mother is going through all
this.
My brother, Bud,
would have been so upset.
And you, demon seed,
acting like you can't hear me
when I'm talking.
You're gonna show me that note.
I can't believe this.
-Come on, boy. Okay.
-Mm-hmm. Uh-huh.
RAY: You're a real tough guy,
ain't ya?
"Mean and surly."
Damn!
♪ I'll stand even when ♪
Yeah, okay, okay,
Aunt Marguerite. Yeah.
Oh, she's doing fine.
Yeah, okay, yeah.
I'll hook that one up.
Yeah-Yeah, okay-okay, okay
yeah I'll hook that one up.
Right.
Well...
good night, Junior.
Good night, Lucille.
♪ Put it all in your hand ♪
♪ And just stand ♪
-♪ Stand ♪
-♪ Even when nights seem cold ♪
Hey, Ray.
♪ When you can't feel
your soul ♪
♪ When your thoughts
won't seem to go away ♪
♪ Go away ♪
Got yourself
a little taste, man.
Yep.
Thought you told Lucille
you quit.
Well, you know how I lie.
Sure is hot out here
tonight, Ray.
(train whistle blows
in distance)
Damn, man, it's hot, Ray.
-Reminds me of that time--
-Sit down, Junior.
Mm. Ahh!
Thanks, Ray.
Sure do appreciate this.
Sure is funny how things
work themselves out sometimes,
ain't it?
Oh, yeah,
I just laugh myself
to sleep every night.
Look, here, Ray.
You know, uh,
I didn't mean none of that
stuff I said up in there.
I-I was real sorry to hear that
Lucille lost that last baby.
I guess she was all tore up
about that, man.
(sighs) We she'd just
quit trying.
'Cause last time
was the absolute worst.
The doctor told her
if she didn't wanna lose it,
she'd have to
lay flat on her back
and not move for nothing.
So, we talked about it, made
a decision to give it one
more shot.
She went to bed.
I went to Rexall to get
a prescription filled.
Get her a bedpan.
Got one of those
chicken buckets...
in case she had to
go while I was gone.
Took a little longer
than I expected, man.
And when I got back,
she had lost it
and didn't even know it.
She lost it
in a chicken bucket, Ray?
A chicken bucket, Junior.
Damn, Ray.
(chuckles)
That's gotta be the most
god-awful story I've ever
heard, man.
Yeah, it was
pretty bad, man.
Well, I was, uh, sort of sorry
to hear about your business
going under.
Yeah, well, thank you, Ray.
(both chuckling)
So, uh, you gonna
tell me or not?
(liquid pouring)
I don't know, Ray, it just
kind of happened, man.
I-I was at the Shopwell
parking lot giving them
a free cleaning.
You know,
sort of as a sample.
And there was this girl, man,
she started loading some stuff
in the back of her car,
and we sort of struck up
this conversation.
So, I started telling her about
the machine, how it worked.
She seemed real interested, man.
I mean-I mean, here I was,
sittin' on top of this big
piece of machinery.
You know, sort of, sort of
the master of it.
And here was this woman...
starin' up at me.
Smilin' at me.
You know, makin' me
feel like a man, Ray.
I was in business, Ray.
I was a businessman,
and I had control of my life.
What happened?
Charisse showed up.
She was lookin'
all hot and sweaty
with all them damn kids
just hangin' off of her, man,
screamin' for a Popsicle.
-(chuckles)
-And you know what
she want to talk about, Ray?
She want to talk about
the house payment.
Want to talk about the car
payment, man. Want to talk about
the kids needin' this and
the kids needin' that, Ray.
And all the time
she was up there talking, man,
I watched that woman pack up
the rest of her stuff
and just drive away.
And all of a sudden, Ray, I got
this strong desire to just...
run Charisse over
with that machine, man.
So, what happened
with the woman, Junior?
(chuckles)
Oh, Bernice Talbot.
-Bernice Talbot?
-Oh, yeah.
Bernice with the--
Oh, yeah, two.
(laughing)
(sighs)
So, what you gonna do?
I don't know, Ray.
I mean, things are
just so messed up now, man.
It's...
I gotta get some money.
You will.
You'll figure it out.
Just not tonight.
(Ray sighs)
Junior, I was thinking
maybe Sunday you could bring
your machine over,
polish up the driveway.
I've been meaning to pay
somebody to do that for me.
That is, if you're not
too busy and all.
Oh, no, no, sure, Ray.
Sunday would be good, man.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
-Thanks, bro.
-Mm-hmm.
Hey, Ray.
I never thought he'd die, man.
Did you?
(radio off)
(chuckles)
REVEREND HOOKER:
Well, friends, it's been another
busy day.
♪♪ (choir vocalizing)
And as I rush
from place to place,
♪♪ (vocalizing)
offering the comfort
and counsel...
to some of our brothers
and sisters in crisis,
catharsis and confusion.
I said to myself,
"Beverly...
what is this thing
called life?"
♪ Praises, dear God
oh, God ♪
REVEREND HOOKER: Is it nothing
but a collection of...
problems, disappointments
and heartaches?
♪ It's all in control ♪
REVEREND HOOKER: Or do we make
it that way ourselves...
with our endless wants,
needs and desires?
♪ My brother just
he's strong ♪
REVEREND HOOKER:
♪ Mmm, Lord ♪
♪ Please let me ♪
And if it is
we, ourselves,
then why do we do it?
-(snoring) - REVEREND HOOKER:
Why don't we "wealize" that
the slender...
and fragile canoe of life
can be so easily overturned...
in the turbulent rapids
of the world?
God's... gonna
handle your problems.
I mean, wh-why don't
we learn to relax?
♪♪ (vocalizing continues)
And why do we
have to call somebody
when we're "twoubled"?
REVEREND HOOKER: Why can't we
can't we just keep it to
ourselves?
God has your problems.
You got to listen to Him.
Trust Him!
Remember, friends,
-our time here is short.
-(shrieks)
And if you feel
that your life is nothing
but the relenting torture,
♪♪ (continues)
-try to make the most of it.
- ♪ But he's working it out ♪
-After all, tomorrow...
- ♪ You have to trust him ♪
-...is another day.
- ♪ God has it all in control ♪
Yes, call God.
Don't call me.
♪♪ (end)
Well, let's see here.
Friends, uh, tonight
we have a new sponsor.
Uh, Depew's Funeral Home.
"Your pit stop
to the afterlife."
Depew's Funeral Home
where longtime Lula resident...
Woodrow Bud Slocumb
is currently in repose.
Mm-mm-mm.
He sure look good.
(together)
Mm-hmm.
Feets look funny, though.
Lucille, my daddy's out here
wearing ballet shoes.
You know how Daddy Bud
always had arthritis
in his feet so bad?
Well, Antoine thinks
when he had his stroke,
that he sort of pointed
his toes down,
and they just sort of
stayed that way.
There was no way
they could get him
in his new shoes.
And with it being so late and
all, they just did the best
that they could.
-I'm gonna kill him.
-Ray! Ray!
-Hi, Lucille.
-Hello there, Merline.
Hey.
Uh, somebody has to organize
this here food.
And then, all these people
have to be out of here
by 8:15...
'cause we have
a Bisons meeting booked
in here after that.
Oh, oh-okay. Well, just take
that on into the kitchen and
I'll be right in.
Thank you so much, ladies.
So nice of you.
Thank you.
I'll be right in.
-Lucille.
-Ray.
Now just go over there
and stand by your daddy
and say hello to the people.
You can do it, okay?
I know you can.
Oh.
(car sputtering)
No, baby, I got it.
I got it.
Hey, Buster. Tiny.
Bud's laid out inside.
Y'all go in.
I'll be right back.
Is there anything
I can get you, sweetheart?
Can you give me back
the last 12 years
of my life, Junior?
Can you give me back
my hopes and my dreams...
of having a loving,
faithful husband?
Can you do that,
Junior?
No.
But I can get you
a Pepsi or something.
A Pepsi's fine,
adulterer.
-(children laughing)
-Damn it!
Junior! Ju--
Junior! Junior!
-That's right. Y'all better run.
-(children chattering)
I'll be right back.
Just a minute.
Pepsi, right?
Pepsi.
(engine starts)
(mouthing)
I love you.
(car backfires)
Come on, baby.
(coughs)
Hey, Bud.
From your mama.
I think you'd better
have a look at that.
"Mean and surly"?
Hmm.
(murmuring)
Oh!
Well, Bud,
they got you painted up
like a two-dollar whore.
♪♪ (humming)
-(Marguerite continues humming)
-Girl, we sure was sorry to hear
about Bud.
Well, I am so glad that you and
Norval could make it.
You know, Norval looks
much better than he did
the last time I saw him.
But since he had his bypass
done and his gallbladder out,
I've noticed
a real improvement.
(yelling)
And next month we're getting
rid of that prostrate,
aren't we, Norval?
CLYDE:
Yeah, it's times like these...
you find out who
your real friends are.
Now they parked their hearse
right out there in the street.
You know?
Anything in the world
can happen to it,
if you catch my meaning.
Uh-huh,
I catch your meaning.
(coughs)
You say the word...
that thing might just
blow up some evening.
Thank you, Clyde.
Yeah. Well, stranger things
have happened, Ray.
That's true, Clyde.
All right, come on.
Come on. Come on.
Come on. Let's just go on
in there and see him.
Now come on.
RAY: All right, Clyde, okay.
Why don't you go on in and
I'll follow you in a minute?
Now, you want me to wait
for you right here?
No, I don't want you
to wait for me right here.
Go on in.
I'll be in, in a minute.
All right.
WOMAN: We gotta keep
that blood pressure down.
WOMAN (yelling): Ain't that
right, Norval?
MARGUERITE: Hmm? What?
Oh, my God!
You get your--
Don't you ever
try to touch me.
You gotta be out of
your ever-lovin' mind!
(scoffs)
Jesus!
♪♪ (woman vocalizing)
What's the matter
with you, boy?
You're supposed to
take care of things.
Look how it all turned out.
Your brother can't keep
his pants zipped up,
your sister's
done fallen in love
with the refrigerator...
and your wife can't have
the one thing in the world
she wants.
Boy, I believe
what you need is a drink.
(water running)
(breathing heavily)
(coughing)
My bad.
My bad, Ray.
Can't look at him,
can you, Ray?
(tires skid)
Damn!
How is she gonna go on,
Aunt Marguerite?
That's what I wanna know.
How's she gonna face life
with--without Daddy Bud?
So sad when a woman
loses her husband.
Mm-hmm. I remember
when I lost my William.
Oh! Nobody to cook for.
Nobody to clean house for.
Nobody to talk to
over the breakfast table.
(whimpering)
♪♪ (humming)
These is my twins right here--
Latanya and Lasanya.
Oh, you are so lucky to have
those precious babies.
Ladies, just find
some space on the counters,
wherever you can.
And this is Tomeka.
She's from my second marriage.
-Excuse me. Has anybody
seen my sister-in-law?
-No.
-Oh, Lord, why is he gone?
-Why is he gone?
Why can't it just all be
the way it used to be?
Oh, Daddy Bud!
-Oh, Lord, the baby!
-Charisse!
-Come on, Charisse.
-LUCILLE: Oh, I got her.
-You got her?
LUCILLE: Charisse,
come on now!
-Pull yourself together!
-Oh!
LUCILLE: Oh, child, I got you!
Come on. Let's go to the
restroom and freshen up.
WOMAN: After I gave him
his injection, irrigate
him for about an hour,
I usually set him on the porch
to watch the sun go down...
while I get supper ready.
But girl I got to be careful.
One time I got to
talkin' on the phone...
and left him out there
for over an hour, mosquitoes
damn near ate his butt up.
Are you gettin'
anything, Norval?
I had the same problem
when my daddy passed away, man.
I guess it was something
about seeing him laid up
like that,
just made me realize, man,
he was really gone.
Wasn't no going back.
He was gone forever.
-That's real consoling, Royce.
-Yeah, man.
You know, he-he look really
good, Ray, for a dead man.
-Hey, hey, hey,
y'all seen Charisse?
-Uh, yeah.
Lucille just dragged her off
to the toilet.
Oh shoot. Man, I mean,
I went all the way down
to the thing
you know to get the Pepsi for
her.
Oh, wow!
Go on.
Look at that there, Ray.
-I don't wanna see him.
-No, he-he look dead, man.
He does.
You-you need to look at him.
I'm sure he does,
Junior.
Um, I'll just leave
you two fellas here...
so y'all can do
y'all thing, you know?
ROYCE: Hey, Ray, I think it
helps to just try and remember
the good times.
-Thank you, Royce.
-All right?
If you can remember any.
You know?
I'll be out back
if you need me.
Well, there it is, Ray.
Look at it.
-Come on, Ray, it's death.
-No.
Come on Ray just look at this...
Just look at the Grim Reaper in
the eye.
He's starin' you in the face.
Stare at him back Ray.
Come on.
-No, Junior. Junior.
-Come on, Ray.
Oh, damn, Ray.
You don't look too good.
-Get me outta here.
-I got got you brother.
Come on.
JUNIOR:
Hey man, how come Daddy got on
them dancing shoes?
(knocks)
Charisse?
-CHARISSE: Yes?
-Honey, we're getting kinda
backed up out here.
I'll be right there.
Okay, hurry up.
She'll be right out.
-Hello, honey.
-Oh, hi!
BOY: Out of the way.
Gotta go. Hi, Mom.
-(people complaining)
-Get outta there you little
bastard!
(no audible dialogue)
Charisse!
Oh, Charisse!
Honey, oh, I'm just
so sorry Teddy Wayne
couldn't be here.
Hi. Hello.
Oh, he always loved
his uncle Bud so much.
But his law practice
is doing so well,
it just keeps him busy
day and night.
What a shame.
(chuckles)
Oh, mama Ray must be
all tore up. Oh.
We better find her.
(chattering)
(exhales)
I can do this.
I can't do this.
(engine starts,
honks horn)
(honking horn)
Course, supper's
his big meal of the day.
But it's always a gamble
if he's gonna be able keep it
down.
But, after I give him
his evening medication
and put him to bed,
he usually sleeps
through the night.
Course, I don't get
much rest myself,
'cause I gotta get up and turn
him every couple of hours.
Mm, I know. You're just so
lucky to have him.
I know.
Where-Where do you want
this Jell-O?
Um... over there.
JUANITA: You know, it's a shame
it takes something this sad
to bring us all together again.
Charisse, do you remember
when Lucille was part of
my royal court...
-when I was elected
Candied Yam Queen?
-No.
CHARISSE: Was that when I was
dating Teddy Wayne?
You know what?
That was such a long time ago.
But you're right Juanita, it is
good to know... Thank you...
that we can come together
like this in a time of sadness.
You are so right, Lucille.
So right.
Mm-mmm.
Now, what can I do
to help?
-Break a nail.
-Um, honey, why don't you, um...
go out there
and make everybody happy?
-You're really good at that.
-It's so sweet of you,
Lucille.
Thank you. I will.
(kisses)
I'll do my best.
JUANITA:
Aunt Marguerite, hi!
You know I could have been
married to that Teddy Wayne
Slocumb if I wanted to.
Oh, Lucille, I could have
been... I could have been rich
and stupid.
I would've been good at it.
But look at me. Look at me.
Who am I now?
I'm poor and foolish
in a trailer.
What happened to me?
LUCILLE: Honey, now, don't you
pay no attention to her.
She just thinks she's happy.
Delightful, sweetie,
why don't you grab
that big bowl over there?
Sweetie, be real careful with it
'cause it was my mother's.
-CHARISSE: But, Lucille!
-You're all right now.
MARGUERITE: Thank you,
Juanita, baby.
So, Aunt Marguerite,
are you still working
with your church groups?
Oh, yes, honey. I'm the
vice president of the Ladies
African Missionary Auxiliary.
-Baby, get that rag,
wipe off over there.
-(loud crash)
(gasps)
Oh, my God.
Delightful?
Y'all go on in the front
because the food ain't out yet.
The food will be out
in about 15 minutes.
-JUNIOR: Is Charisse
still in there?
-WOMAN: Excuse me.
Charisse? Come on, baby,
people out here are
beginning to talk about you.
You not going to stay in there
all night, is you, Charisse?
Baby?
Now you know you
the only woman for me.
I knew that
the first time we went out.
You remember that night...
that we went down to
the Dairy Whiz and I bought you
that grape fizzy cream,
you know, the one you like?
JUNIOR: We sat out on that sofa
that your pops had out
in the front yard...
-(laughing)
-and talked about our future and
feeling so good,
-like, like we had our
whole lives ahead of us.
-(crowd) Aw.
Look, baby, you know
I ain't good at this,
but, I don't know, standing out
in that parking lot,
I guess I lost my head.
So now I'm... I'm praying that
you might maybe
want to take me back.
You know, because if I learned
one thing from you, Charisse, is
that I am nothing without you.
-(toilet flushes)
-Okay, baby?
You are my world, Charisse,
and I love you.
Oh, Charisse, baby.
ROYCE: I love you too, Junior.
You could of told me
it was you, Royce.
-Well, at least it was quick.
-Mm-hmm.
That's the best way, quick.
You don't want to linger.
Tha--That'd be awful.
Quick.
Yeah, that's the way
I want to go--quick.
Car crash, bolt of lightning.
Piano...
hitting you on the head.
That's what I want.
That's what I want
for you, Clyde.
Yeah, me too.
God, you and I both know
there ain't nothing in this
liquor store...
that can help me
or the ones I love.
So if you could figure out
a way to get this car started...
before I reach
for this door handle,
I sure would appreciate it.
Evening, Ray.
Reverend. Mrs. Hooker.
How are you?
We're about to go over
to Depew's and visit with
your family for a little while.
You want to follow us
over there?
You bet, Reverend.
-Okay.
-(engine starts)
-(exhales) Thank you, God.
-Oh, hey, Bernice.
-So, uh,
-have you seen Royce?
-Uh, no, honey. Not in a while.
Well, um, I hope y'all
can you use this.
Well, thank you, Bernice.
(coughs, gags)
-LUCILLE: Ooo, that's awful.
-Oh! No, uh-uh.
We're about to start
real soon, Merline, okay?
real soon, all right?
Oh, Delightful,
honey, do me a favor.
Take and put this somewhere up
in the kitchen up high where
can't nobody get to it, okay?
-Whoo! That's just
a bowl full of funk.
-That's Bernice's dish.
-Is that Bernice Talbot?
-Uh-huh.
-She looks a god-awful mess.
-LUCILLE: Charisse.
Well, she ain't... never been no prize
to nobody, and you know she'll lift
that skirt up for anybody who'd ask.
Poor thing.
JUANITA: I saw her not two weeks
ago, staggering out some old
Cadillac...
with her blouse on backwards
and one earring hanging off.
Just tacky.
-MARGUERITE: Mm-mm.
-JUANITA: What?
-All right, y'all--
-Hey, has anybody seen Charisse?
LUCILLE: Let's get started,
okay? You know, I think we
oughta get started.
Bernice Talbot?
LUCILLE: What did I say?
Charisse. Now, honey, now,
-there are a lot of people--
-My husband done did it...
to that child
in the Shopwell parking lot?
Lord, take me now!
People, don't pay her no mind,
she just likes attention.
-All right, y'all--
-Will you quit harping on that?
-Get up before you
make your dress dirty.
-(Charisse wailing)
LUCILLE: All right, come on
y'all. Now we got a lot of good
food up here. Come on.
We got baked beans,
macaroni and cheese,
some greens, some yams.
And look, somebody
even brought us some--
(crying)
Who brought this?
Lucille?
Honey, what's wrong?
CHARISSE: What am I gonna do?
What am I gonna do?
-Get out! Out!
Out! Out!
-(laughing)
-Lu-Lucille?
-Leave me alone!
-Oh, God!
-Charisse!
Come on out of here.
Don't nobody care about
your husband and Bernice Talbot.
(screams)
If you don't come out of here,
I'm gon--
I'm gonna sic
Delightful on you.
-Please, just let me
come in for just a second.
-Just leave me alone!
You just don't understand!
I don't understand?
Honey, you think
you're the only one
with heartache, huh?
I'll have you know I have a son
in the penitentiary.
You don't see me wallowing on
the flo', you don't see me
hiding up in somebody's closet.
Well, this closet's taken,
and you can't have it!
Move!
Let me tell you
one thing, young lady.
You listen to me.
Like it or not, we are family.
We are the Slocumbs,
and we are going to
serve this dinner...
with our heads held high
if it kills us.
Now you come on.
You come on outta here!
MARGUERITE:
Come on, people,
get your plates. Take these--
Pass these plates out.
We ain't got all day.
I am so glad you could come,
Reverend. Good to see you.
Mrs. Slocumb,
I'm so sorry for you,
and I'm glad that I can be here.
I'm just so sorry, Ray.
Thank you, Charles.
Thank you.
You know, I had no idea
your daddy was a dancer.
Well, it was a pretty
well-kept secret, Charles.
We thank you, Lord,
for these blessings.
And last but not least, Lord,
you know the names
of all the men in this room...
-who've done filthy things
with Bernice Talbot.
-(all murmuring)
I don't need to repeat
their names, Lord,
-but I could,
if I was provoked, amen.
-(all) Amen.
In Jesus' name, amen.
Everybody step lively,
we have to eat up.
A bunch of Bisons
booked this room next,
and they ready to eat.
♪ People try and say
I always understand why ♪
Bombs away!
♪ The rain falls on thee ♪
♪ And I have to admit ♪
♪ I feel my faith is gone ♪
♪ It's easy to believe ♪
♪ When sorrow
never comes your way ♪
♪ And when I try to pray ♪
♪ It seems the words
they come out wrong ♪
♪ So everything
that matters to me ♪
♪ I give it all to you ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm tired of the way
the cryin' feels ♪
♪ And just to let you know ♪
Yeah, well.
Look, I just wanted to call,
make sure you guys got in
the house okay; make sure
everything was all right.
Yeah...
no, Ray, we here.
We'll be home
in a little bit.
All right.
Sure hated not being able to
visit with everybody.
It's just so sweet,
all those people.
Each of them touched
in some way by Daddy Bud.
They was touched all right.
Now I want you to see if
Junior can use these shirts,
'cause you know
he's gonna be looking
for a job soon.
-We don't want him out there
looking like a scarecrow.
-I will.
About ready to go, honey?
No, I'm gonna talk to Mama
for a little while.
You don't mind, do you?
-Not at all. Get some rest.
-I will.
-Good night, Mama.
-Night, honey.
♪ Thy Kingdom come ♪
♪ Oh thy will be done ♪
(clears throat)
Ray?
Mama, Antoine told me
what you requested
on that stone.
I'm not having it.
It's gonna say,
"Rest In Peace,"
which is eleven letters,
so Antoine's gonna give us
a two-dollar credit.
That's it, Mama.
Period. That's it.
All right.
I understand that.
Well, that's all I had to say.
I'll let you get to bed now.
-Come on, take a minute
with me. Can you?
-Of course, Mama.
I want to show you something.
Come on, help me up.
Do you remember these?
Can't say I do.
These were
my embroidery scissors.
My mother gave them to me
after I married your father.
I used to do all kinds
of things with these.
Did all the quilts,
made clothes for you kids.
Just... everything.
And one day
they just up and disappeared.
I looked everywhere for 'em,
I tore this house up.
I never saw them again.
And yesterday,
when I went looking for
your daddy's good cuff links,
I found them
in with his stuff.
I can't for the life of me
figure out what he wanted
with them.
Never even occurred to me
to ask him if he knew
where they were.
Isn't that funny?
I guess so, Mama.
It came to me that your father's
like these scissors.
We didn't lose him
on Wednesday.
We lost your father
a long, long time ago.
Did you love him?
Sometimes I loved him,
sometimes I hated him, Mama.
RAYNELLE: Ray, sometime...
when you're not even
thinking about it,
a little door's gonna
open up inside of you.
And you'll be feeling
just fine about however
you feel about your daddy...
'cause it'll be right;
you'll be able to accept it.
♪ Yesterday I got a page
and it said ♪
♪ That my daddy died
but I couldn't cry ♪
♪ We had a fight
long time ago ♪
♪ By the liquor store
said I didn't want to
see your face no more ♪
-Night, Mama,
see you tomorrow.
-All right.
♪ I don't understand ♪
♪ The telephone rings
and what am I
supposed to do ♪
Mama.
Hmm?
You sure about
that door opening?
Absolutely positive.
-Now you know
if you need anything--
-Lucille,
don't try to fix it.
Let's just let it be
broke for awhile.
(car engine starts)
♪♪ (vocalizing)
♪ I've been up
I've been down ♪
♪ Been looking for some joy
to come around ♪
♪ I've been praying
for some sunshine ♪
♪ Been looking for a love
that I can call mine ♪
♪ See, I've cried for so long ♪
♪ Now I'm ready for the tears
to be gone ♪
-♪ So, I'm calling you
right now ♪
-♪ Right now ♪
♪ 'Cause you said I could
make it, Lord, anyhow ♪
MARGUERITE: Come on, Delightful,
quit fidgeting.
Royce! Wake up.
Well, where's
Aunt Raynelle at?
Why?
Are you in a hurry, Devil? Huh?
Delightful, come on.
Uh-uh. No, no, no.
None of that today.
And take that gold
fake thing out your mouth.
I don't want that--
Delightful, come on!
(arguing, indistinct)
-♪ So I'm goin' away ♪
-♪ Are you ♪
-♪ 'Cause I know that
you're gonna pull ♪
-♪ Me through ♪
-♪ Hallelujah, come on, y'all ♪
-♪ Lead me through
Be strong ♪
♪ 'Cause I know that deliverance
is comin' in ♪
-♪ It won't be long
I'll wait ♪
-♪ Hallelujah ♪
-♪ It's gonna be ♪
-♪ A brighter day ♪
-♪ Can't you finally see ♪
-♪ The sun ♪
-♪ I'm gonna wait till ♪
-♪ Thy kingdom come ♪
Lucille, I can't find
my good pants.
Lu!
♪♪
-♪ I believe it's gonna be ♪
-♪ A brighter day ♪
-♪ Can't you see it
I finally see it ♪
-♪ The sun ♪
-♪ So I'm waitn' on you till ♪
-♪ Thy kingdom come
-♪ So I'm gonna wait ♪
-♪On you ♪
-♪ Must have known
that you're gonna pull ♪
-♪ Me through ♪
-♪ Can't you hear him
he's telling you ♪
-♪ Be strong ♪
-♪ 'Cause I know deliverance
is comin' in ♪
-♪ It won't be long ♪
♪ Well ♪
♪ Well-well-well ♪
(man groaning,
bowel noise)
Where the hell
is the preacher, Mama?
We ain't
in a big rush, Ray.
Mama, Antoine and Merline
are charging me by the hour.
Ray, go on
and find him.
Sit tight.
-Lucille, come on. Come on!
-Shh.
-What's he doing?
-He'll be out in a minute, Ray.
I'm going broke waiting for him.
Tell him to get out here.
LUCILLE: It seems last night
that Reverend and Mrs. Hooker
celebrated their anniversary.
And since it was
a special occasion,
they decided to try that
new Mexican restaurant
up in Tempton.
-So what!
-Well, it seems this morning the
reverend's having a little...
intestinal difficulty.
Lucille, I swear to God,
if I have to go in there myself,
I'll tear it off the hinges.
I've had it up to here
with this shit!
Ray, now that is
a poor choice of words, okay?
You know my nerves
are getting worked,
-and I don't have my
nerve pills on me today.
-Just calm down. Shh, shh.
-I'm trying to be--
-Just take a deep breath.
Come on. I know.
-(exhales)
-I'm really trying.
I know.
I'll take care of
it, okay? Be quiet.
(sighs)
-(knocking on door)
-Reverend?
(farts)
Shouldn't be much longer.
Be okay.
-When's this thing gonna start?
-In a minute.
Charisse?
Honey, where's Junior?
I don't know,
ask Bernice Talbot.
(laughs)
Charisse--
Girl, you so funny.
You want some gum?
No, thank you.
I always carry a pack
of sweet gum with me
at weddings and funerals.
I think it's something
about the rhythm of it
that sort of lulls me.
Helps my mind wander.
You want to know
what I think about
when my mind wanders?
Well, I'm sure
you're going to tell me.
I think about my life.
How at the end of each day,
I tuck my precious
little boy into bed,
turn out the lights
in my $800,000 home,
crawl into my
king-size bed
and lie there and wonder...
where the hell
my husband is.
You sure you don't
want a piece?
Why don't you
leave him?
And go where?
Charisse, I got everything
I ever asked for.
-But he really loved you--
-Then I might be forced into
that god-awful position
of having to love him back.
-Do you love Junior?
-I just--
Oh--mm.
Do you want him back?
You don't have to
answer that right now, honey.
Just sit back
and let the sweet gum
take its effect.
It'll come to you.
(breathes deeply)
Hot in here.
-That's nice.
-Thank you, girl.
Can I see it?
WOMAN: How you doing?
Uh, first of all, let me
apologize for my tardiness.
Say why I was late,
I had to call the gas company.
There seemed to be a problem
with one of the pipes.
(clears throat)
Um, shall we pray?
-JUNIOR: Sorry.
-(congregation murmuring)
Sorry I'm late,
I had to--
For God's sake, sit down.
-Sit down!
-(stammering)
Sit down!
Heavenly Father,
we come here today
with heavy hearts...
I'm sorry.
...as we mark with sadness
the passing...
of our dearly departed
Brother Bud Slocumb.
(paper bag crackling)
Give us peace
in our hearts today, Lord.
Guide us through the long night,
and help us see the promise...
-Psst!
-of a better tomorrow.
Okay, you need to
handle this.
I'm gonna move.
REVEREND HOOKER: Now--Now,
Father,
let that tomorrow...
be better day
than yesterday was.
For what is yesterday...
but the tomorrow
that we thought we could not
face the day before.
-(congregation) Amen. Amen.
-(paper bag crackling)
(clears throat)
But, God, with your help,
we face it anyway.
Just like we'll face today,
tomorrow and all of
our days to come...
till You call us home
to be with You...
and our beloved Brother Bud.
Can everybody say "Amen"?
(congregation)
Amen.
-I love you, Charisse.
-(all murmuring)
Can't you understand that?
I love you.
(congregation gasps)
I guess you thought you could
just waltz into
your daddy's funeral...
with a Whizzy Cream
and that would make
everything okay.
And I was just supposed to
forget about all the pain...
and humiliation that
you have put me through,
huh, Junior?
-All right now, Raymond, it's
your daddy's funeral, okay?
-I'm gonna stop it.
I'm just supposed to
welcome you with open arms...
and say, "I forgive you, Junior,
I forgive you, I forgive you!"
Well, yeah.
-I love you, Junior.
-Oh-ho, I love you too,
Charisse.
CHARISSE:
Why do you have to
do me like that, Junior?
JUNIOR:
Oh, I didn't mean to
do you like that, baby.
-I'm sorry, I love you.
-That's it! That's it!
Get in the pew!
That's it!
Get your ass in that pew!
Stay there if you
value your life.
That's it!
Now, is there anything else...
that anybody else here
needs to say or do?
Does everybody here
have everything they need?
This family may be
the laughingstock around here,
but for once in our lives,
we're gonna do something
with class...
and dignity.
All right, Reverend...
take it away.
Well, o-okay there,
Ray.
Um... well.
(stammers)
Ain't God good?
-Um...
-(congregation agrees)
Let's see.
Now I did not know
Brother Slocumb well,
but to me,
he seemed to be a quiet man.
A man of inner strengths.
And I believe that--
-(stomache rumbling)
-(gulps, clears throat)
Ooh. Now I believe that...
if he was here today,
he would send a message
to his family.
The message would
simp-simp-simply...
-say--
-(farts)
-(congregation gasps)
-Oh, uh-oh.
(farts)
(continues farting)
Would you all don't mind
just excusin' me
for just a minute?
-Imma--Imma be right back.
-(farts)
-MAN: Don't bring it over here.
(laughing)
You gotta admit, he always was
a man of few words.
Baby, it doesn't matter
if we have children or not.
-What?
-It doesn't matter
if we have a baby.
-You're all I ever wanted.
-Oh, Ray.
I hate to break up
this little party,
but how are we going to
have a funeral
if there is no pastor?
Sit down, Marguerite.
We don't need no pastor.
RAYNELLE: We got Ray Bud. Go on
up there and say a few things.
Feel that
little door opening.
-Go on, say it for us.
-Go on, baby.
(exhales loudly)
You can do it.
Aunt Marguerite,
you wanna?
Oh. Well, thank you, Ray.
Um, there seems to be
a passage here in Isaiah
that um, says, "Whoa--"
Hey, Ray.
What about that part
from Psalms, man?
The part that goes, uh,
"Though my father
and mother forsake me...
then the Lord
will take me up.
Teach me thy way, O Lord,
and lead me in a plain path,
and let me see
the goodness of the Lord
in the land of the living.
Wait on the Lord
and be of good courage,
and He shall
strengthen thine heart.
Wait, I say, on the Lord."
You got it, Ray.
That was real good, Royce.
That was real good.
Uh...
I guess this is the part
where I'm supposed to...
tell you all how great a man
my father was.
Well, I'm not
gonna do that.
I'm gonna do what
he would've done.
I'm gonna tell the truth.
My father was a hard man.
I'm not judging him, I just--
It's just the facts.
Daddy wasn't real big
on soft words.
And I know
he wasn't good at...
expressing what he felt
in his heart.
So, as I stand here today,
I can tell you this.
If I could do one thing
all over again...
I'd tell my father
I loved him,
instead of waiting
my whole life...
for him to tell me first.
So, as you step up here today...
to say your last good-bye...
to Woodrow "Bud" Slocumb...
I hope you'll open up
the door to your heart.
RAY: I hope you'll take time and
take a moment
to truly consider the folks
in your life that mean
something to you.
Because people
don't last forever.
RAY: They really don't.
And letting a person in,
that's the most cherished
treasure this life has to offer.
So, I'm proud to
stand here today...
and say that in his own way,
my father taught me that.
Amen.
-(all) Amen.
-Amen baby.
Hooo!
(chuckles)
Uh, we are truly lucky...
to have with us today...
a member of our family.
Mrs. Charisse Marie Slocumb,
who is going to honor
her father-in-law in song.
Charisse.
-Thank you.
-Thank you, Ray.
I haven't sang it
in a long time.
(laughs)
CHARISSE: I know you all know
this, so sing along.
♪ Everybody needs ♪
♪ Somebody who'll be there ♪
♪ Someone to wipe the tears
and make you smile ♪
♪ And if you need someone ♪
♪ Who will not judge you
when you fall ♪
♪ No matter what you've done ♪
♪ My love will answer
when you call ♪
♪ So after your friends
have walked away ♪
♪ And you run out of
words to say ♪
♪ After you've tried
everything else ♪
♪ Then try me ♪
♪ Even though you hurt me ♪
♪ And sometimes
forget my name ♪
♪ My love is unconditional ♪
♪ That means that it won't
ever, ever change ♪
♪ After your heart's
been torn in two ♪
♪ And you just don't know
what to do ♪
♪ After your doubts
have come and gone ♪
♪ And the sun
still won't shine ♪
♪ After your friends
have walked away ♪
♪ And you run out of words
to say ♪
♪ After you've tried
everything else ♪
CHARISSE:
♪ Try me ♪
♪♪ (gospel)
(coughs)
Baby, you were wonderful.
Baby, that was good.
Um, uh, uh, well, Daddy...
I know you always wondered
about me and the kids.
But uh, I just want to
let you know you don't
have to worry no more,
because Charisse is going to
be in the music business,
and I'm going to be her manager.
-You think?
-Oh, I think.
-RAY: Sure does look peaceful,
don't he?
-Yes, he does.
Daddy Bud, I want you to know,
in about 7 1/2 months from now,
you might be getting
a little surprise.
And if it's a boy,
we're going to name him
Buddy Ray.
And if it's a girl,
we're going to name her
Budicia Joy.
But just don't get
your hopes up too high yet.
Bye, Daddy.
♪♪ (gospel)
Well, Royce, when I go,
just put me out in a pine box.
You don't have to spend
no money on me. Not that
you're going to have any.
Well, Mama,
when the time comes,
you just make sure
you point your toes down
like Uncle Bud here.
That way I can go on
and put you right in the ground
with a pile driver.
Oh, Royce,
you just a demon.
But I'm your demon mama.
(laughing)
-Royce, come on, baby.
-(growls)
(screams)
No, you didn't!
If it starts to
get crowded up there, Bud,
save a place for me.
But not too soon.
(all saying good-bye)
-♪ La la la la la la ♪
-♪ Mary Mary ♪
-♪ La la la la la la la ♪
-♪ Thank you ♪
-♪ When I look back over
my life ♪
-♪ Thank you ♪
-♪ And all the times
you brought me through ♪
-♪ Thank you ♪
♪ I just wanna say, Father
thank you ♪
♪ When I was lonely
and needed someone
to hold me ♪
♪ Oh, you were beside me
when my nights
were cold and lonely ♪
-♪ Oh, you never
let me down when ♪
-♪♪ (indistinct)
♪ Always count on you
to see me through ♪
♪ I'm telling you that
you are the reason ♪
♪ I'm alive
and I'm still breathing ♪
♪ For me you gave your life
and now my life
it has new meaning ♪
♪ When I think about your grace
and I finally see your face ♪
♪ There's one thing
I need to say
want to say, yeah ♪
♪ Thank you, Lord
for loving me ♪
for keeping me ♪
♪ Thank you for that day
you came and broke the chains
and set me free ♪
♪ Thank you for another chance
You gave me joy
now I can dance ♪
♪ All my people open up
your mouth and let me hear
you say thank you ♪
-♪ Thank you ♪
♪ Thank you, Lord
for one more day ♪
-♪ You made the raindrops
go away ♪
-♪ Hey, hey ♪
♪ Thank you 'cause my pain
it's gone ♪
♪ I know it came
to make me strong ♪
♪ Thank you for another chance
You gave me joy
now I can dance ♪
♪ All my people open up
your mouth and let me hear
you say thank you ♪
-♪ Thank you ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
-♪ All the children say ♪
-♪ Yeah, yeah
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
-♪ All my babies say ♪
-♪ Thank you ♪
-♪ For making a way out
of no way, Lord, I ♪
-♪ Thank you ♪
-♪ For my health
and strength, Lord, I ♪
-♪ Thank you ♪
-♪ For helping me
say thank you ♪
-♪ Thank you ♪
♪ Thank you, Lord
for loving me ♪
for keeping me ♪
♪ Thank you for that day
you came and broke the chains
and set me free ♪
♪ Thank you for another chance
You gave me joy
now I can dance ♪
♪ All my people open up
your mouth and let me hear
you say thank you ♪
♪ Thank you
Thank you ♪
♪ Thank you ♪
♪ Thank you, Lord
for one more day ♪
♪ You made the raindrops
go away ♪
♪ Thank you
'cause my pain it's gone ♪
♪ I know it came
to make me strong ♪
♪ Thank you for another chance
You gave me joy
now I can dance ♪
♪ All my people open up
your mouth and let me
hear you say thank you ♪
-♪ Thank you
Thank you ♪
-♪ Thank you ♪
♪ Thank you, Lord
for loving me ♪
for keeping me ♪
♪ Thank you for that day
you came and broke the chains
and set me free ♪
♪ Thank you for another chance
You gave me joy
now I can dance ♪
♪ All my people open up
your mouth and let me
hear you say thank you ♪
-♪ Thank you ♪
♪♪ (ends)
♪♪
♪ Everybody needs ♪
♪ Somebody who'll be there ♪
♪ Someone to wipe the tears
and make you smile ♪
♪ So if you need someone ♪
♪ That will not judge you
when you fall ♪
♪ No matter what you've done ♪
♪ My love will answer
when you call ♪
♪ So after your heart's
been torn in two ♪
♪ And you just don't know
what to do ♪
♪ After the rain
has come and gone ♪
♪ And the sun
still won't shine ♪
♪ After your friends
have walked away ♪
♪ And you've run out of
words to say ♪
♪ After you tried
everything else ♪
♪ Try me
Oh, yeah ♪